<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Localization on Yu Zhou</title>
    <link>/tags/localization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Localization on Yu Zhou</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Yu Zhou</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/localization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dog-Drone</title>
      <link>/project/dog-drone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/dog-drone/</guid>
      <description>From March to June 2018, I worked on the proof-of-concept phase of the “Dog-Drone” project.
The objective is to immobilize suspicious individuals in an indoor environment by flying multiple drones aggressively around them. My work includes the following:
 Human detection and tracking Trajectory generation System integration  This work has resulted in papers published in the IEEE ICCA and IECON 2018.
   Video 1. Dog-Drone demo
At this stage, to prove the concept, we are using the off-the-shelf flight platform with a visual odometry integration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unmanned Ground Systems Challenge</title>
      <link>/project/unmanned-ground-systems-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/unmanned-ground-systems-challenge/</guid>
      <description>Along with 3 other teammates from the State Key Laboratory of Robotics, I participated in the Unmanned Ground Systems Challenge in October 2016 and worked specifically on the environment map building and localization under GPS signal lost situation.
This challenge was held in a real field environment, including wild battlefield task execution, city battlefield search and investigation, and highland transportation.
Fig. 1. Our UGV platform
Environment Map Built an environment map for non-structured fields with the following steps:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>